<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.salvogendut.Emulator1985</id>
  <name>1985</name>
  <summary>Amstrad PCW 8256 emulator</summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0-only</project_license>
  <developer id="io.github.salvogendut">
    <name>Salvatore Bognanni</name>
  </developer>
  <description>
    <p>
      1985 is an Amstrad PCW 8256 emulator written in C with SDL3, a
      sibling project to 1984 (CPC). The PCW family ran CP/M Plus on
      a Z80 with a Motorola 6845 CRTC driving a 720x256 monochrome
      green-phosphor display, an NEC uPD765A floppy controller, and
      256 KB of banked RAM addressed in 16 KB pages.
    </p>
    <p>
      The PCW has no boot ROM — a 778-byte bootstrap stream is
      injected at reset, builds a 256-byte loader in RAM, and that
      loader pulls the system from drive A. 1985 reproduces this
      behaviour and ships no firmware ROMs.
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.salvogendut.Emulator1985.desktop</launchable>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/salvogendut/1985</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/salvogendut/1985/issues</url>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <releases>
    <release version="0.4.7" date="2026-07-13">
      <description>
        <p>PerryFi gains a PerryNet binary-protocol mode with TCP, UDP, pull-based receive and firmware time support. A browser-based Web GUI now provides isolated, sandboxed sessions with web audio streaming. Pilot/autopilot control supports scripted testing, and the default monochrome monitor uses the brighter reference green tint.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.5" date="2026-07-02">
      <description>
        <p>Screen-accuracy fix: the F8 50/60 Hz status bit had inverted polarity, so CP/M configured a 200-line NTSC screen — AMX Desk's desktop was clipped and its trash bin unreachable. The full 256-line PAL screen now works, the F-key strip moved to its own band so the CP/M status line row is no longer covered, and a new Advanced "Status line" toggle can hide that row the way real CRT overscan does. Video rendering is ~2.5x faster. New --disk-event CLI flag scripts mid-run disk swaps for headless testing.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.4" date="2026-06-30">
      <description>
        <p>New 8 MHz Z80 Turbo toggle on the General tab. Camera-shutter sound effect when you take an F4 screenshot. The built-in beeper now keeps its audio sample rate across cold resets. Flatpak builds are now produced from main and published as a release asset.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.3" date="2026-06-28">
      <description>
        <p>On-screen toast notifications for disk-open failures, serial PTY readiness and PerryFi dial-outs — F9 ▸ Advanced ▸ Notifications cycles screen / console / off. LED hover labels reveal what each status LED represents. Real CRT post-process gains adjustable scanline, brightness, contrast and per-channel RGB controls under Advanced. Media tab overlay panel resized so the "Enter / Del" hint no longer clips.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.2" date="2026-06-26">
      <description>
        <p>PCW built-in beeper (boot-ROM error tones, CP/M BEL, +/- and F7/F8 keys all audible). Multilink probe-stub at ports 0xA6/0xA7 prevents Multilink-aware software from hanging. Boot ROM search now walks the XDG data and config paths; new Advanced row shows the resolved path with picker and clear. Advanced "Version" row also shows the git commit.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.1" date="2026-06-26">
      <description>
        <p>CF2DD blank disc spec fix — drive-B writes now work on PCW 8512/9512 and on 8256 with the Second drive accessory. Overlay file pickers (Drive A/B, blank create, snapshot Load/Save) remember the last directory used. Windows build persists config under %APPDATA%/1985 instead of next to the .exe.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.0" date="2026-06-23">
      <description>
        <p>F9 ▸ General reorganised: PCW Backplane now lives here and gates the whole Extensions tab; Second drive moved here too (8256 only). Floppy LED B is hidden when the running model has no second drive. Printer LED hides when the backplane is unplugged. Man page refreshed.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2026-06-21">
      <description>
        <p>Initial scaffolding: SDL3 window, F9 overlay framework copied from 1984, Z80 core wired against PCW memory and I/O ports (0x00/0x01 FDC, 0xF0-0xF3 banking, 0xF4-0xF8 ASIC, 0xFC/0xFD printer status), 778-byte boot stream + boot loader at 0x0002. PDF printer output is available from the Extensions overlay.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
